ALI HUSNAIN SHAH

.NET Developer

x ahshah2211@gmail.com

+923196989322

in linkedin.com/in/ahshah322/

• Kharian, Pakistan

https://ahshah-portfolio.netlify.app/

PROFILE

.NET Developer with 3+ years of professional experience in designing, developing, and maintaining software applications using the .NET framework. Expertise in C#, ASP .NET MVC, .NET Core, Blazor, SQL Server, and PostgreSQL with a strong understanding of object-oriented programming principles. I possess a deep passion for technology and strong problem-solving skills with a commitment to continuous learning, and staying up-to-date with emerging technologies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

.NET Developer, Hybrid Tech PK

January 2024 - March 2024 | Kharian, Pakistan

- Design, develop, and maintain software applications using C#, .NET Framework/Core MVC, WinForm, Syncfusion, SQL Server, SQLite, and Bootstrap.
- Collaborate with teams on requirements analysis, design, and architecture
- Write clean, well-optimized, and efficient code
- Test and deploy applications ensuring functionality and performance
- Troubleshoot and debug existing code for improvements

Senior Software Engineer, Dolphin Digital OOH Media

June 2022 – October 2023 | Plano, USA

- Improved performance by resolving more than 80 critical bugs in the company's products
- Development of server-side software using .NET Core 6/7, Blazor, and PostgreSQL
- Designed front-end using Blazor component library like MudBlazor
- Implemented different tools to import and export data in Excel
- Applied fixes and enhancements to SQL scripts through PostgreSQL

.NET Developer, APKSoft

February 2022 – July 2022 | Kharian, Pakistan

- Managed 6+ website projects including business, e-commerce, and portal
- Enhanced the application's features to effectively fix the bugs and optimize the overall performance, reliability, and efficiency
- Designed web pages using HTML, CSS, CHTML, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, and page design and layout
- Utilized ASP .NET, ASP MVC, SQL Server, and Microsoft Visual Studio for development
- · Build RESTful API's with ASP.NET Web API

EDUCATION

MASTER OF COMPUTER SCIENCE, Government College University Faisalabad 2019 – 2021 | 3.9/4

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, University of Gujrat 2017 – 2018





Creativity and innovation

Time Management

Organisation

Analytical thinking

LANGUAGES

English

Urdu

Punjabi

